I have some suggestions to help you improve
your listening scores.
Firstly, you should do listening exercises with increasing
difficulty.
You should start with easy ones, such as
sentence completion and short answer questions, and remember
to practice each of them carefully.
After finishing, you should analyze which question you
answer incorrectly, why you make those mistakes, find
and learn new vocabulary.
Our goal is to increase the percentage of
correct answers to 80%.
By doing that, you will be less pressured
when practicing other question types.
If you haven't mastered the easy exercises yet,
it's likely that you will give up difficult
ones.
In the next phase, you will practice more
difficult question types.
They are summary completion.
For this one, you have to listen for
many synonyms.
If you don't know the synonyms of words,
it's likely that you can't find the answers.
The next one is flowchart, and then map
completion.
These question types assess your sensitivity and reflexes
when you listen.
For example, if you haven't identified the east
-north direction on the map while the speaker
is talking about it, how can you find
the answers?
Other question types you can practice are matching
or multiple-choice questions.
You need to choose the correct answer from
a wide range of options.
When all the options are mentioned by the
speaker, which answer would you choose?
Just by hearing the keywords, it's really difficult
to choose the correct one.
So, when practicing these types, please follow all
the steps I introduced to you so that
you can get your desired scores.